<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>School on Walter Mays</title>
    <link>http://waltermays.com/categories/school/</link>
    <description>Recent content in School on Walter Mays</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 23:32:44 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://waltermays.com/categories/school/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally (heh) Over</title>
      <link>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/12/finally-heh-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 23:32:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/12/finally-heh-over/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m done. I&amp;rsquo;m finally done with finals. It&amp;rsquo;s been a heck of a semester.
My classes were&amp;hellip; well, meh, for the most part. Computer Engineering was a challenge, as was Computer Science. I didn&amp;rsquo;t do as well as I would like in Linear Algebra (retrospectively, I could have, but I slacked off a little too much at the beginning of the semester). UNIX was a joke, as everyone told me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I&#39;m Moving Away From LaTeX</title>
      <link>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/03/why-im-moving-away-from-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/03/why-im-moving-away-from-latex/</guid>
      <description>This may come as a shock to you: I, Walter Mays, the ardent LaTeX fanatic, am not going to use LaTeX for every assignment anymore. What is this world coming to?!
It&amp;rsquo;s not that I&amp;rsquo;m going to stop using LaTeX completely. I think that is a fantastic system for typesetting structured documents, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been having to put together several of those this semester. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t trade the power of LaTex for the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Woah. I Understand Now</title>
      <link>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/02/woah.-i-understand-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/02/woah.-i-understand-now/</guid>
      <description>Those of you who have been following my blog know that I posted something called &amp;ldquo;The End Is Nigh,&amp;rdquo; in which I disparaged those who felt overwhelmed by school. Oh how the turntables&amp;hellip; All it took was a good dose of too many credit hours.
I was doing a healthy 15 credit hours last semester; this semester it&amp;rsquo;s up to 19. That isn&amp;rsquo;t to say I&amp;rsquo;m not enjoying it. I&amp;rsquo;m not, but that&amp;rsquo;s not why.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The End Is Nigh!</title>
      <link>http://waltermays.com/blog/2017/12/the-end-is-nigh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://waltermays.com/blog/2017/12/the-end-is-nigh/</guid>
      <description>Dead week has begun. When not in their rooms studying, sleepless students with glazed eyes and racing thoughts slowly pace the hallways, eager for a break from relentless business, mathematics, and computer science assignments. And throughout all of Kaufmann, young, clueless freshmen are crying out, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s all the fuss about?&amp;rdquo;
I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I&amp;rsquo;m doing something wrong, but the end of my first semester seems eerily easy. To be sure, I have a few big tests coming up, some of which count for a large percentage of my grade.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>