<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Walter Mays</title>
    <link>http://waltermays.com/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Walter Mays</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://waltermays.com/categories/personal/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Internship Post-Mortem</title>
      <link>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/08/internship-post-mortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/08/internship-post-mortem/</guid>
      <description>On Friday I finished my internship at CBOE. Quite honestly I&amp;rsquo;m going to miss working there; I learned a lot, both from my coworkers and from the codebase. In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to go over what I liked (and disliked) about my summer internship.
The Known Unknowns Going into this internship, I knew that I would have to learn how to properly develop software with others. Most of my prior experience involved me writing a program to solve a problem or complete an assignment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First &#39;Real&#39; Programming Job</title>
      <link>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/05/my-first-real-programming-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/05/my-first-real-programming-job/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I started my first internship at Cboe Global Markets. Hooray! I&amp;rsquo;m getting paid to do what I do for fun anyway!
I was expecting it to be difficult, and it is, but it&amp;rsquo;s certainly not as difficult as I was led to believe. Obviously I can&amp;rsquo;t talk about anything that I&amp;rsquo;m working on in detail (NDAs and all that), but I can say that I&amp;rsquo;m being much more productive than I expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I&#39;m Moving Away From LaTeX</title>
      <link>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/03/why-im-moving-away-from-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/03/why-im-moving-away-from-latex/</guid>
      <description>This may come as a shock to you: I, Walter Mays, the ardent LaTeX fanatic, am not going to use LaTeX for every assignment anymore. What is this world coming to?!
It&amp;rsquo;s not that I&amp;rsquo;m going to stop using LaTeX completely. I think that is a fantastic system for typesetting structured documents, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been having to put together several of those this semester. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t trade the power of LaTex for the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Stupid Accident</title>
      <link>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/03/my-stupid-accident/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/03/my-stupid-accident/</guid>
      <description>For those of you who see me every day (or, in the case of my parents, had to deal with this mess), you already know the story. For everyone else: I got in a car accident on February 13th. It was the stupidest accident I&amp;rsquo;ve ever heard of.
I wasn&amp;rsquo;t hurt, and the other drivers weren&amp;rsquo;t hurt. It was about as fortunate as an accident like this can be.
First off, some backstory: I noticed a few days earlier that my wheel was wobbling somewhat when I drove.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Aftermath</title>
      <link>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/02/the-aftermath/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/02/the-aftermath/</guid>
      <description>Good news everyone! I finished my first session as a GM, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t die! I&amp;rsquo;ve found a few strengths and many weaknesses, but I at least have some idea what&amp;rsquo;s going on.
The Preparation I have a couple of close friends who have been GMs before. Neither of them has tons and tons of experience, but they have a good idea of what they&amp;rsquo;re doing. They recommended that I watch all of Matt Colville&amp;rsquo;s Running the Game series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Absolutely Terrified</title>
      <link>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/02/im-absolutely-terrified/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/02/im-absolutely-terrified/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to start being a Game Master for a D&amp;amp;D game on Friday. I have no idea what I&amp;rsquo;m doing.
That&amp;rsquo;s not exactly true. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a world that a friend built, I&amp;rsquo;ve got a few ideas going in, and I&amp;rsquo;ve got some generators I can use. But going into something like this with exactly zero experience is always going to be nerve-wracking.
I&amp;rsquo;ve never run an encounter. I&amp;rsquo;ve never run a battle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Woah. I Understand Now</title>
      <link>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/02/woah.-i-understand-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/02/woah.-i-understand-now/</guid>
      <description>Those of you who have been following my blog know that I posted something called &amp;ldquo;The End Is Nigh,&amp;rdquo; in which I disparaged those who felt overwhelmed by school. Oh how the turntables&amp;hellip; All it took was a good dose of too many credit hours.
I was doing a healthy 15 credit hours last semester; this semester it&amp;rsquo;s up to 19. That isn&amp;rsquo;t to say I&amp;rsquo;m not enjoying it. I&amp;rsquo;m not, but that&amp;rsquo;s not why.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Third Failed Game Jam</title>
      <link>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/01/my-third-failed-game-jam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://waltermays.com/blog/2018/01/my-third-failed-game-jam/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with game development for several years now. I&amp;rsquo;ve researched engines and frameworks, looked into drawing, level design, and music programs, and thrown around ideas. I even started programming a few of them. Guess how many I&amp;rsquo;ve finished.
I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one with this problem. Most &amp;ldquo;game developers&amp;rdquo; never really get much farther than a working prototype of a few of their core mechanics. While that can be fun &amp;mdash; if you call fiddling with weights until the movement doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to floaty or heavy &amp;ldquo;fun&amp;rdquo; &amp;mdash; it&amp;rsquo;s not as fulfilling as (I imagine) completing a game would be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The End Is Nigh!</title>
      <link>http://waltermays.com/blog/2017/12/the-end-is-nigh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://waltermays.com/blog/2017/12/the-end-is-nigh/</guid>
      <description>Dead week has begun. When not in their rooms studying, sleepless students with glazed eyes and racing thoughts slowly pace the hallways, eager for a break from relentless business, mathematics, and computer science assignments. And throughout all of Kaufmann, young, clueless freshmen are crying out, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s all the fuss about?&amp;rdquo;
I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I&amp;rsquo;m doing something wrong, but the end of my first semester seems eerily easy. To be sure, I have a few big tests coming up, some of which count for a large percentage of my grade.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>